Run Codex non-interactively

Usage: codex exec [OPTIONS] [PROMPT]
       codex exec [OPTIONS] <COMMAND> [ARGS]

Commands:
  resume  Resume a previous session by id or pick the most recent with --last
  review  Run a code review against the current repository
  help    Print this message or the help of the given subcommand(s)

Arguments:
  [PROMPT]
          Initial instructions for the agent. If not provided as an argument (or if `-` is used), instructions are read from stdin. If stdin is piped and a
          prompt is also provided, stdin is appended as a `<stdin>` block

Options:
  -c, --config <key=value>
          Override a configuration value that would otherwise be loaded from `~/.codex/config.toml`. Use a dotted path (`foo.bar.baz`) to override nested
          values. The `value` portion is parsed as TOML. If it fails to parse as TOML, the raw string is used as a literal.
          
          Examples: - `-c model="o3"` - `-c 'sandbox_permissions=["disk-full-read-access"]'` - `-c shell_environment_policy.inherit=all`

      --enable <FEATURE>
          Enable a feature (repeatable). Equivalent to `-c features.<name>=true`

      --disable <FEATURE>
          Disable a feature (repeatable). Equivalent to `-c features.<name>=false`

  -i, --image <FILE>...
          Optional image(s) to attach to the initial prompt

  -m, --model <MODEL>
          Model the agent should use

      --oss
          Use open-source provider

      --local-provider <OSS_PROVIDER>
          Specify which local provider to use (lmstudio or ollama). If not specified with --oss, will use config default or show selection

  -p, --profile <CONFIG_PROFILE>
          Configuration profile from config.toml to specify default options

  -s, --sandbox <SANDBOX_MODE>
          Select the sandbox policy to use when executing model-generated shell commands
          
          [possible values: read-only, workspace-write, danger-full-access]

      --full-auto
          Convenience alias for low-friction sandboxed automatic execution

      --dangerously-bypass-approvals-and-sandbox
          Skip all confirmation prompts and execute commands without sandboxing. EXTREMELY DANGEROUS. Intended solely for running in environments that are
          externally sandboxed

  -C, --cd <DIR>
          Tell the agent to use the specified directory as its working root

      --add-dir <DIR>
          Additional directories that should be writable alongside the primary workspace

      --skip-git-repo-check
          Allow running Codex outside a Git repository

      --ephemeral
          Run without persisting session files to disk

      --ignore-user-config
          Do not load `$CODEX_HOME/config.toml`; auth still uses `CODEX_HOME`

      --ignore-rules
          Do not load user or project execpolicy `.rules` files

      --output-schema <FILE>
          Path to a JSON Schema file describing the model's final response shape

      --color <COLOR>
          Specifies color settings for use in the output
          
          [default: auto]
          [possible values: always, never, auto]

      --json
          Print events to stdout as JSONL

  -o, --output-last-message <FILE>
          Specifies file where the last message from the agent should be written

  -h, --help
          Print help (see a summary with '-h')

  -V, --version
          Print version
